<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><!DOCTYPE changelog SYSTEM "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MuntashirAkon/AppManager/master/schema/changlelog.dtd">
<changelog>
    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v4.0.0"
        code="440"
        date="10 February 2025">
        <note subtext="true">
            Private messages should be emailed to am4android@riseup.net. Emails sent to any other
            email addresses shall be discarded.
        </note>
        <note subtext="true">If you're running ADB, you may need to restart your device first.</note>

        <new>New logo for App Manager!</new>
        <new>A dedicated page for debloating the phone</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            Debloating profiles were available as “Presets” in the Profiles page which has now been
            replaced with the Debloater page which can be accessed from the three-dots menu in the
            Main page. [a href="https://github.com/MuntashirAkon/android-debloat-list"]ADL[/a] is a
            new project focused on maintaining a list of bloatware as well as potential open source
            alternatives.[br /][br /]

            Color codes for the list:[br /]
            - Dark cyan: The app is safe to remove. It does not necessarily mean that the app should
            be removed as it is always up to the user[br /]
            - Sand color: The app is safe to remove, but removing it might break one or more
            features[br /]
            - Orange: The app may or may not be safe to remove[br /]
            - Red: The app is not safe to remove.[br /]
            [br /]

            Batch operations:[br /]
            - Uninstallation[br /]
            - Enable/disable[br /]
            - Save APK[br /]
            - Create new profile[br /]
            - Add to profile.[br /]
            [br /]

            On clicking an item, the following information are displayed with:[br /]
            - App icon (valid only when the app is installed)[br /]
            - App label[br /]
            - Package name[br /]
            - App info button (if the app is installed)[br /]
            - Tags[br /]
            - Warning (if available)[br /]
            - Description with references[br /]
            - Dependencies[br /]
            - Suggestions/alternatives.[br /]
            [br /]

            In addition to the typical search option, there are several filtering options available
            in this page:[br /]
            1. Categories: AOSP, OEM, Carrier/ISP, Google, Miscellany, and Pending[br /]
            2. Types: Safe (i.e., safe to remove), Replace (i.e., should be replaced with
            alternatives), Caution (i.e., generally safe to remove but no guarantees), Unsafe (may
            cause bootloop)[br /]
            3. Other: User apps, System apps (mutually exclusive), Installed apps and Uninstalled
            apps (mutually exclusive).
        </note>
        <new>An (almost) fully-featured File Manager</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            Features:[br/]
            - Thumbnail previews for media files, pictures, PDFs, ePubs, OpenDocument files, APK,
            APKM, APKS, XAPK, J2ME JAR files[br/]
            - Sorting options: name, size, and last modification date with folders on top[br/]
            - Filtering options: toggle dot files[br/]
            - File operations: copy, cut, rename, delete[br/]
            - New folders, links, and empty files, such as text files, PDF, documents (docx/odt),
            sheet (xlsx/ods), presentation (pptx, odp), and SQLite3 database[br/]
            - Opening folders from third-party apps[br/]
            - Path navigation to easily navigate to different locations[br/]
            - Batch operations: file operations and sharing[br/]
            - Other operations: sharing, creating shortcuts, open with[br/]
            - Settings: set default home directory, remember last opened folder and position, and
            whether to display the file manager as “Files” in the app drawer[br/]
            - Displaying file/folder properties.[br/]
            - Favorites (i.e., bookmarks).
        </note>
        <new>Integrated code editor</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            Manifest and code viewers have been replaced with this new editor. Among other regular
            features, it includes proper syntax highlighting and advanced searching options. In
            addition, files from third-party apps can also be opened for editing.
        </note>
        <new>New widget: Data usage</new>
        <note subtext="true">Display total download and upload speed for today.</note>
        <new>Added options for runtime optimization in Android 7 or later</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            This option is available for all apps in the 1-click ops page and individual app in the
            three-dots menu in the app info tab.[br /][br /]

            Features:[br /]
            - Set Compile filters, such as speed-profile or everything-profile[br /]
            - Compile layout resources[br /]
            - Immediate optimization of DEX, i.e., somewhat similar to [tt]pm force-dex-opt[/tt]
        </note>
        <new>Save install, batch and profile operations to history</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            Each history entry remembers everything necessary to allow it to be re-executed.
            However, any re-execution attempt may still fail for the following reasons:[br/]
            1. The history entry has certain apps requirements that are no longer installed[br/]
            2. The history entry may rely on external files that are no loner available or
            accessible to App Manager[br/]
            3. The privilege has changed (e.g., previously it was executed with root but now
            no-root)[br/]
            4. The operating system no longer supports the functions[br/]
            5. App Manager no longer allows the operation.[br/][br/]

            When a profile is re-executed from history, it preserves the same applications and
            configurations used at that point in time in order to ensure the consistency of
            operation.
        </note>
        <new>Replaced log viewer, sys config, Terminal, etc. with Labs page</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            Labs is a new page where various handy tools are listed. They include Sys Config,
            Log Viewer, Terminal (not an actual Terminal emulator), File Manager, UI Tracker,
            Interceptor, History, and Code Editor.
        </note>

        <!-- 1-Click Ops page -->
        <title type="medium">1-Click Ops page</title>
        <new>
            Added option to uninstall apps that were previously uninstalled without clearing data.
        </new>
        <improve>Replace “Block components…” with “Block/unblock components…”</improve>
        <note subtext="true">Components can also be unblocked using the option.</note>

        <!-- App Details page -->
        <title type="medium">App Details page</title>
        <new>Allowed launching non-exported activities in no-root/ADB mode</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            The “Search assistant” (usually set to Google Assistant) feature allows setting
            arbitrary activity via the [tt]assistant[/tt] key-value pair stored in the secure
            settings database. Hence, non-exported (that is, app private) activities can be launched
            even in no-root mode by exploiting this feature. However, modifying a secure setting
            require [tt]android.permission.WRITE_SECURE_SETTINGS[/tt] permission which is granted
            automatically in ADB mode and has to be granted manually in no-root mode via ADB.[br /]

            App Manager also cannot trigger the assistant on its own in the no-root mode, because it
            doesn't have enough permissions (it requires [tt]android.permission.INEJECT_EVENTS[/tt]
            permission which cannot be granted to the user applications). Activity shortcuts also
            use this feature when they cannot be launched in privileged mode.
        </note>
        <improve>Display blocking method in the components tabs</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            IFW+Dis = The component is blocked using both IFW and disable[br /]
            IFW = The component is blocked using IFW[br /]
            Dis = The component is disabled.
        </note>
        <improve>Improved loading performance</improve>
        <fix title="App Ops">Prevented crashes in Samsung devices running Android 6.0.1</fix>
        <fix>Disabled “IFW” and “IFW+Disable” in the providers tab</fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            In Rules settings, the description for “Default blocking method” was also updated with a
            note that says IFW feature does not work with providers, “disable” is used for them
            instead.
        </note>
        <fix>Fixed applying IFW method in the components tabs</fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            Fixed applying IFW rules if the previous rules were “IFW+Disable” or “Disable”.
        </note>
        <fix>Fixed setting mode for some app ops</fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            In the app ops tab, the toggle button as well as the long click options attempts to
            alter the associated permission too if it exists. [u]To bypass this behaviour, use
            “Set custom app op” from the three-dots menu instead.[/u]
        </note>

        <!-- App Info tab -->
        <title type="medium">App Info tab</title>
        <new>Added option to enable/disable sensors</new>
        <new>New tag: Bloatware</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            Clicking on the tag opens a dialog containing description, dependencies, alternatives,
            etc. like in the Debloater page.
        </note>
        <new>New tag: Open links</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            “Open links” is displayed for apps capable of opening links from the verified domains
            without any user intervention. This feature, added in Android 12, has raised privacy as
            well as usability concerns, because it promotes tracking and reduce user's freedom of
            choice. Therefore, in active state, that is, when the app is able to open the links
            directly, this tag will have a “red” background (otherwise, it will have a “green”
            background).[br /][br /]

            On clicking the tag, a list of supported domains will be displayed in a dialog (although
            not all domains can be opened by default). If the user has enough permissions, an option
            to enable/disable the behaviour will be displayed. Otherwise, an option to open the app
            details page in the Android Settings app will be displayed.
        </note>
        <new>New tag: Sensors disabled</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            System may misreport this permission. The best way to check if sensors are indeed
            disabled is by opening the app first and then visiting the App Info tab leaving the
            other app running in the background.
        </note>
        <new>New tag: Static shared library</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            The tag is displayed for static shared libraries, that is, the apps with
            [tt]static-library[/tt] tag in their manifest files, requires root or ADB. Clicking on
            the tag displays a dialog with a list of libraries installed under the same package
            name, and offer the user to uninstall the selected libraries.
        </note>
        <new>New tag: Xposed</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            Clicking on the tag opens a dialog with more details:[br /]
            1. Module name[br /]
            2. Description[br /]
            3. Type of module (modern or legacy)[br /]
            4. Xposed API dependency info[br /]
            5. Scope (if available statically).
        </note>
        <improve>Added an option to create a new profile in the “Add to profile” dialog</improve>
        <improve>Avoid listing split APKs “Paths &amp; Directories” section</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Split APK info are already displayed in the corresponding tags above this section. There
            is no reason to display them again.
        </note>
        <improve>Display detailed installer info</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            An info button is added next to the installer which displays the installer, the actual
            installer (AKA initiator), and the APK source (originator). Clicking on each item opens
            the corresponding App Details page. It also fixed displaying the installer app in
            certain devices.
        </note>
        <improve>Improved performance by loading UI contents in the background</improve>
        <improve>Hide data usage for other users</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Data usage section is hidden if the following conditions are true:[br /]
            1. OS is Android 6.0 onwards[br /]
            2. The app does not belong to the current user, and[br /]
            3. Self or remote UID is not system UID.
        </note>
        <improve>Hide “Data usage” for apps without the internet permission</improve>
        <improve>List SAF files and directories in a user-friendly manner</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Instead of a raw representation of the granted URI, display authority, type of file or
            folder, and the file or folder itself in a meaningful way. It also attempts to retrieve
            the original file path when possible.
        </note>
        <fix>Fixed displaying wrong information regarding blocked trackers</fix>
        <fix>Fixed handling multiple users in no-root mode</fix>
        <fix>Prevented crashes in tablets running buggy GSI firmware</fix>
        <fix>
            Prevented the app from crashing on attempting to enable battery optimisation of
            restricted apps
        </fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            Battery optimisation cannot be enabled for system restricted apps.
        </note>
        <fix>Use the configured naming format when sharing an APK(S)</fix>

        <!-- App Usage page -->
        <title type="medium">App Usage page</title>
        <improve>Improve the "Usage Widget"</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            - Replaced old colors with the new ones[br/]
            - Fixed padding issues in Android 12 onwards[br/]
            - Set an upper limit for the widget (350dpx450dp)[br/]
            - Utilized the dynamic text sizing on Android Oreo onwards[br/]
            - Use secondary colors instead of the default colors for labels[br/]
            - Use dynamic colors if available[br/]
            - Hide bubbles/circles if available apps is &lt; 3[br/]
            - Added a refresh button[br/]
            - Support automatic switching between light and dark mode[br/]
            - Added a dark theme preview.
        </note>
        <improve>Improve the usage time calculation method</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            The usage events returned by the [tt]UsageStatsManager[/tt] were assumed to be in order
            of their timestamp which does not seem to be true and resulted in missing a few events
            due to the standard calculation method, that is, calculating the time difference between
            activity resume and pause timestamps. In addition, it appears that the system may log
            activity stop timestamp without logging any pause timestamp (a typical activity cycle
            would be resume → pause → stop → resume → …) causing further miss of events. These
            issues were addressed by sorting the events in order of their timestamp as well as
            measure the time difference between resume and stop timestamps instead of resume and
            pause timestamps.
        </note>
        <improve>Fetch data usage for all apps in Android 5 and 5.1</improve>
        <improve>Fetch usage stats and package size info only when the feature is enabled</improve>
        <improve>Make the combo-box (spinner) static on top</improve>
        <improve>Reduced lags by recycling views</improve>
        <fix>Fixed retrieving mobile data usage in Android 12 and earlier</fix>
        <fix>Fixed the “times opened” value</fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            In order to calculate a more reliable number of times an app was opened, the time
            difference between each activity opening and closing are now relaxed. So, when the user
            navigates to another activity from an activity belonging to the same app and the time
            difference is less than 500 ms, the time difference is added to the total usage time.
            This calculation is technically more precise than the system's own open count because
            certain navigation involves the use of system UI (e.g., the arrow in the gesture
            navigation is emitted from the System UI app and should be considered as such) which are
            ignored. However, the issues with choosing 500 ms (half of a second) time difference are
            as follows:[br /]
            1. Due to an user waiting a long time to trigger the back gesture or simply bad coding,
            an app may take more than this time to open an activity which will cause them to be
            listed as two accesses.[br /]
            2. Some apps support multiple windows. If the user opens another activity in a new
            window shortly after opening the first activity, the two accesses may be counted as one
            instead of two.[br /]
            These events are considered extraordinary and can be negligible in a real-life setting.
        </note>
        <fix>Take device shutdowns into account while calculating app usage</fix>

        <!-- Backup/restore -->
        <title type="medium">Backup/restore</title>
        <new>Enable experimental support for Zstandard (ZSTD) compression</new>
        <improve>Display backup extras and rules in no-root mode</improve>
        <improve>Improved handling custom users in backups</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            - Properly handle backup/restore for a single app. “Custom users” in the backup options
            is displayed only if the app is installed for multiple users. Similarly, cross-user
            restore is supported via the “Custom users” option. In addition, fixed issues causing
            the backup or restore to be performed for the wrong users.[br /]
            - Unless the “Custom users” option is selected, backup or restore is made only for the
            current user in the batch selection mode. Others retain the old behaviour. For example,
            in the batch selection mode, restore is only made with the “base” backup which is
            defined to be the primary backup for the current user. So, if “Custom users” option is
            selected for restore operation, App Manager will try to find the base backup of each
            selected user and restore those for that user.[br /][br /]
            These behaviours are applied throughout the app to reduce complexity and remove
            any ambiguous behaviour.
        </note>
        <improve>Log the reason for a failed APK installation during restore</improve>
        <fix>Alphanumerically sort app data to prevent restoring issue</fix>
        <fix>Fixed creating custom backups</fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            When custom backups are enabled but the backup name is empty, create a custom backup
            with the current date and time instead of creating a base backup.
        </note>
        <fix>Fixed the “cache” “no cache” confusion in the backup flags selection dialog</fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            The “No cache” flag was replaced by the “cache” flag, but the translations still use the
            former. So, the string ID is altered to invalidate the translations.
        </note>

        <!-- Explorer -->
        <title type="medium">Explorer</title>
        <improve>Avoided decoding AXML files</improve>
        <note subtext="true">Decoding should be done by code editors, not explorers.</note>
        <improve>Specially handle APK files to prevent parsing errors</improve>
        <fix>Fixed opening files with external editor/viewer</fix>

        <!-- Freeze/unfreeze -->
        <title type="medium">Freeze/unfreeze</title>
        <new>New freeze option: Advanced suspend</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            Allows an app to be both force-stopped and suspended to prevent it from running in the
            background.
        </note>
        <improve>Added curated freeze method selection option</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Apart from selecting a default freeze method in the Settings page, it is also
            possible to do the following:[br /]
            - Set per-app freeze method. This allows setting a non-default freeze for each app. The
            option can be accessed by clicking the "Freeze" button in the App Info tab of an app.
            The per-app freeze method will also be backed up and restored as part of the "Extras"
            backup flag.[br/]
            - Set per-operation freeze method. All freeze-related batch operations (in the Main and
            Debloater pages) and the "Freeze" option in App Info tab display a dialog button that
            allows a user to choose a non-default, per-operation freeze method.
        </note>
        <fix>Prevented the app from crashing if a shortcut icon is immutable</fix>

        <!-- Installer -->
        <title type="medium">Installer</title>
        <new>Added an option to perform DEX optimisation immediately after installing an app</new>
        <new>Added the ability to modify installer options before installing an app</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            In the installation dialog, clicking on the settings/cog icon opens a new dialog where
            the installer options can be temporarily set for the session. Any items queued for the
            session will retain those temporary options.
        </note>
        <new>Added the option to align APK files before signing</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            When APK signing is enabled, enabling this option will ensure that the contents of the
            APK are aligned properly before the APK is signed. Since it doesn't modify the contents
            of the APK, the option is enabled by default.
        </note>
        <improve>Accelerate the installation process in Android 12 onwards when possible</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            If an app is being installed in the foreground, App Manager will try to accelerate the
            installation process by delaying various post-installation tasks carried out by the
            system services.
        </note>
        <improve>Display installation progress in the notification</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            In some devices such as Samsung, it takes an indefinite amount of time to verify the app
            after copying the APK files. For those cases, the progress won't be accurate as it only
            takes into account the amount of time to copy the files.
        </note>
        <improve>
            Display “Confirm install” notification even if the app is running in foreground
        </improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            In no-root mode, when the app is running in foreground, the user may accidentally
            dismiss the install-confirmation dialog produced by the Android package installer which
            would either allow the installation to run forever or for a minute until the timeout
            occurs. To solve the issue, a silent notification is triggered at the same time the
            dialog is shown so that even if the user accidentally dismisses the dialog, the dialog
            can still be displayed by clicking the notification.
        </note>
        <improve>Enabled installing system apps with a different signature</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            The “Install only” button is enabled for system apps when the signatures are different.
            This is useful for only those who have disabled signature verification using methods,
            such as CorePatch.
        </note>
        <improve>
            Enabled opening the App Details page of an app installed by App Manager from Android
            Setting's App Info page.
        </improve>
        <improve>
            Properly handle the originating URI extra supplied by third-party apps via
            [tt]Intent.EXTRA_ORIGINATING_URI[/tt]
        </improve>
        <improve>Set originating package in Android 7 onwards</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            The originating package is automatically determined from the Intent sent from the
            third-party apps. However, the determination logic may not always work, but it was
            ensured that there will not be any false positives, e.g., no spoofing can be done by a
            third-party app.
        </note>
        <improve>
            Set package source to [tt]PACKAGE_SOURCE_OTHER[/tt] by default in Android 13 onwards
        </improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            This is done to prevent the system from applying various accessibility restrictions to
            the app. However, [tt]PACKAGE_SOURCE_STORE[/tt] is set by default if the originating
            package is one of the supported app stores. At present, the supported app stores are:
            Aurora Store, Droid-ify, F-Droid, F-Droid Basic, F-Droid Classic and Neo Store. It is up
            to the developers to ensure that they send the APK installation requests in a proper
            way, i.e., by utilizing features such as [tt]startActivityForResult[/tt] whenever
            possible.
        </note>
        <fix>Added workaround for updating system apps in HyperOS 2.0</fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            If [tt]INSTALL_FAILED_HYPEROS_ISOLATION_VIOLATION[/tt] is triggered in the privileged
            mode, the installer will try again with the installer set to [tt]com.android.shell[/tt].
        </note>
        <fix>
            Fixed displaying re-installation prompt for apps that were uninstalled without clearing
            data
        </fix>
        <fix>Fixed installing APK files queued in the background</fix>
        <fix>Fixed installing some signed APK files</fix>
        <note subtext="true">Some signed APKs could not be installed due size mismatch.</note>
        <fix>Fixed parsing unsigned APK files</fix>
        <fix>Fixed installing apps for users other than the main profile</fix>

        <!-- Interceptor -->
        <title type="medium">Interceptor</title>
        <improve>Added a few intent filters related to camera</improve>
        <improve>Intercept SAF, dialer, gallery, search, music player, and WhatsApp URLs</improve>
        <fix>Fixed retrieving matching activities when a default is set</fix>
        <fix>
            Prevented the app from crashing when creating a shortcut with invalid extras or icon
        </fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            Shortcuts support only 11 types of data structures. Intents, on the other hand, support
            any type of data structures. When a shortcut creation is requested, the unsupported data
            structures are removed from the Intent to avoid crashes.
        </note>

        <!-- Log Viewer -->
        <title type="medium">Log Viewer</title>
        <new>Added a batch option to copy the selected logs</new>
        <improve>Changed list selection modes.</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            1. Normal mode[br /]
            - Click: expand/collapse text[br /]
            - Long click: Open context menu[br /]
            2. Selection mode[br /]
            - Click: Select clicked item[br /]
            - Long click: Select items between the last selected item to the clicked
            item if possible. Otherwise, only click the item.
        </note>
        <improve>Improve searching and filtering</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            logcat has been migrated to [tt]threadtime[/tt] format from [tt]time[/tt] with backward
            compatibility. Searching now supports Android Studio conventions:[br/]
            - Supported keywords are: [tt]msg[/tt], [tt]pid[/tt], [tt]pkg[/tt], [tt]tag[/tt], and
            [tt]uid[/tt]. Any other non-keyword filtering are matched against the log messages
            (e.g., they are appended to the [tt]msg[/tt] tag). [tt]uid[/tt] is only supported in
            Android 7 and later[br/]
            - Each keyword takes the intended arguments followed by a [tt]:[/tt] (colon) (e.g.,
            [tt]pid:1[/tt] denotes filtering all the logs produced by the PID 1)[br/]
            - All keywords are [tt]and[/tt]'ed together (e.g., [tt]pid:1651 tag:Ime[/tt] means
            filtering all the logs with the tag containing [tt]Ime[/tt] belonging to the PID 1651)
            [br/]
            - Adding a [tt]-[/tt] (minus) before a keyword denotes exclusion (e.g.,
            [tt]-pid:13[/tt] denotes listing all logs except PID 13)[br/]
            - Adding a [tt]~[/tt] (tilde) sign before [tt]:[/tt] (colon) denotes a regular
            expression match[br/]
            - Adding a [tt]=[/tt] (equal) sign before [tt]:[/tt] (colon) denotes an exact match
            (e.g., [tt]tag:Ime[/tt] filters any logs with a tag containing the string [tt]Ime[/tt]
            whereas [tt]tag=:Ime[/tt] filters any logs with a tag that is equal to [tt]Ime[/tt]).
            [tt]pid[/tt] and [tt]uid[/tt] keyword always do an exact match unless it is a string
            or regular expression.[br/]
            - [tt]~[/tt] (tilde) and [tt]=[/tt] (equal) signs are mutually exclusive with [tt]~[/tt]
            (tilde) preferred over [tt]=[/tt] (equal), i.e., when both signs are present, only
            [tt]~[/tt] (tilde) sign is used for regular expression matching[br/]
            - Non-exact and non-regex filters are always case insensitive.
        </note>

        <!-- Main page -->
        <title type="medium">Main page</title>
        <new>Added a new filtering option “Stopped apps“ to filter the force-stopped apps</new>
        <new>Added filtering by users in the list options</new>
        <new title="Batch Ops">
            Added a new batch operation “Optimise” to dex optimisation of the selected apps
        </new>
        <new title="Batch Ops">Added an option to export app list as CSV and JSON</new>
        <improve>
            Avoided reopening the keyboard while searching is active, but the keyboard was closed
            manually
        </improve>
        <improve title="Batch Ops">
            Added an option to create a new profile in the “Add to profile” dialog
        </improve>
        <improve title="Batch Ops">
            Display configured net policy if only one app is selected
        </improve>
        <improve>
            Display a prompt to fully uninstall apps that were uninstalled without clearing data
        </improve>
        <improve>Display restore dialog for uninstalled apps with backups</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Instead of displaying “App not installed” toast for the uninstalled apps with backups,
            open the restore dialog instead when clicking on such an item in the Main page.
        </note>
        <improve>Display static libraries in privileged mode</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Static libraries such as Trichrome Library are only visible to system, shell, root and
            the apps which depend on it. Using privileged mode, it is possible to list them in the
            Main as well as perform typical operations on them.[br /][br /]

            For non-rooted users, these libraries are only visible in the “Shared Libs” tab (in App
            Details page) of the apps that depend on them.
        </note>
        <improve>Display user count alongside app ID</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            If an app is installed in more than one profiles (that is, for multiple users), instead
            of displaying only the kernel user ID (UID), display the app ID (i.e., UID sans the user
            ID) and user count in the following format:[br /][br /]

            [tt]&amp;lt;user count&amp;gt;+&amp;lt;app ID&amp;gt;[/tt]
        </note>
        <fix>
            Fixed retrieving applications when there are too many applications installed on the
            device
        </fix>
        <fix title="Batch ops">Fixed saving APKS with dependencies</fix>
        <fix title="Batch Ops">Fixed saving some APK files due to naming issues</fix>
        <fix>Prevented crashes when the installer feature is disabled</fix>

        <!-- Profile page -->
        <title type="medium">Profile page</title>
        <new>Added an option to copy profile ID</new>
        <improve>Display app op names instead of number in the profiles page</improve>
        <improve>Display exit confirmation dialog if there are unsaved changes</improve>
        <improve>Display previously selected apps on top of the app list</improve>
        <improve>Display warning before deleting a profile</improve>
        <fix>Avoid creating duplicate profiles by auto-renaming the newly-created profile</fix>
        <fix>Fixed displaying backup options in configurations tab</fix>
        <fix>Fixed loading label after refreshing the app list</fix>

        <!-- Profiles page -->
        <title type="medium">Profiles page</title>
        <new>Added an option to copy profile ID</new>
        <new>Use profile ID instead of profile name for identifying each profile</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            In profile version 1, there's no difference between profile name and profile ID. But from profile version 2,
            a new field [tt]id[/tt] shall be introduced which will be decoupled profile name from its ID, making it
            possible to use any name for profile or rename it. [u]If you use automation, make sure to use profile ID
            instead of profile name.[/u]
        </note>
        <improve>Auto-select the configured profile state in “Apply profile” dialog</improve>
        <improve>
            Avoid displaying a completion notification when a profile triggered through automation
        </improve>
        <improve>Handled applying multiple profiles using a queue</improve>
        <improve>Moved shortcut handling logic to a different activity</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            To avoid opening existing tasks from Recents, shortcuts are handled in a separate task.
        </note>
        <improve>Optimised updating new or modified profile information</improve>
        <fix>Fixed applying profiles</fix>

        <!-- Running Apps page -->
        <title type="medium">Running Apps page</title>
        <improve>Display available memory</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            According to Linux's [tt]meminfo[/tt] specs, "available memory" is the amount of memory
            the kernel can allocate to a new process whereas "free memory" denotes the amount of
            memory not utilized by the kernel.
        </note>
        <improve>Refresh running apps every 10 seconds</improve>
        <fix>Fixed listing processes when some PIDs no longer exist</fix>

        <!-- Scanner -->
        <title type="medium">Scanner</title>
        <new>Display link to Pithus report if available</new>
        <improve>Calculate file hashes more efficiently</improve>
        <improve>Migrate to VirusTotal v3 API</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Allows uploading a single file with size up to 650 MB (compared to only 32 MB in API v2
            in the free plan)
        </note>
        <fix>Fixed scanning external APK files in privileged mode</fix>

        <!-- Security -->
        <title type="medium">Security</title>
        <improve>
            Check for zip-slip vulnerability before creating a folder or a symbolic link
        </improve>
        <improve>Disabled access to [tt]content://[/tt] in WebView</improve>
        <improve>Improved security of the shortcuts created within App Manager</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Earlier, opening the shortcuts of exportable activities did not require any
            authentication. From now on, authentication is required for opening any new shortcuts.
        </note>
        <improve>Only allow connections from supported online locations</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            To avoid issues with ADB, localhost is allowed unrestricted connections, but other
            websites, namely virustotal.com and pithus.org, are restricted via SSL pinning using
            network security configuration.
        </note>
        <improve>Sanitize user inputs, intents when it involves files and filenames</improve>
        <improve>Use formatted string for logging to prevent log injections</improve>

        <!-- Settings page -->
        <title type="medium">Settings page</title>
        <new>Added options to run App Manager in the background</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            In Settings > Privacy, two new options have been added:[br /]
            1. Run App Manager in the background[br /]
            2. Automatic lockdown[br /]
            [br /]

            Running App Manager in the background makes the annoying “Initializing” screen go away.
            Due to possible privacy issues, this option is disabled by default. When automatic
            lockdown is enabled, App Manager will attempt to lock the app by killing its process.
            As expected, there are several side effects:[br /]
            1. All the activities will be closed. They'll be reopened by the system based on how the
            user was interacting with them[br /]
            2. All the running operations as well as scheduled or running jobs will be stopped
            immediately. This might cause data loss if potentially destructive operations are
            running.[br /][br /]

            Note: Enabling the latter option does not wipe the memory of App Manager, i.e., it does
            not prevent a forensic software from scrapping the memory used by App Manager even if
            the process no longer exists.
        </note>
        <new>Added option to disable sending notification to the connected devices</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            The setting is located at [a href="app-manager://settings/advanced_prefs"]Settings >
            Advanced > Send notifications to the connected devices[/a] and is enabled by default.
            Low importance notifications, e.g., ongoing notifications and optional alerts, won't be
            delivered to the connected devices even if the setting is enabled.
        </note>
        <new>Added support for pure black theme</new>
        <new>Support running custom command for mode of ops</new>
        <improve>Added a fallback server runner command from DE storage</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Added a fallback server runner command in case SD card is inaccessible from the UID from
            which the script is being run. This leverages the device encrypted storage (data_de) by
            making certain folder and files globally accessible.
        </note>
        <improve>Avoided auto-detecting ADB port number if Wi-Fi is inactive</improve>
        <improve>Display ADB pairing dialog directly when a pairing may be required</improve>
        <improve>Improved "About the device" dialog</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Display build number, graphics model, Vulkan version, battery technology, estimated
            battery capacity (which is the real battery capacity), battery health, battery cycle
            count (in Android 14 onwards), dm-verity, verified boot, AVB version, bootloader
            lock/unlock state (only when AVB is enabled), debuggable OS, Android KeyStore features,
            encryption algorithms supported by the hardware- and the StrongBox-backed keystore.
        </note>
        <improve>Improved auto-connecting to ADB</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            - When mode is set to auto, instead of checking the active ADB host and port first, the
            status of the ADB daemon is checked[br /]
            - When mode is set to “Wireless debugging”, developer settings and wireless debugging
            are enabled automatically before attempting any connections. This requires:[br /]
            1. [tt]android.permission.WRITE_SECURE_SETTINGS[/tt] to be granted to App Manager, OR[br /]
            2. App Manager connected via root or ADB at least once (in which case, the permission
            above is granted automatically)[br /]
            - Attempt to fetch the current port for ADB over TCP via [tt]service.adb.tcp.port[/tt]
            property instead of using the default [tt]5555[/tt] port or the previously saved value.
        </note>
        <improve>Improved preferences and dialogs</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            - Added a dedicated page for VirusTotal[br /]
            - Added a dedicated page for mode of operations[br /]
            - Moved “Use the Internet” to Privacy settings[br /]
            - Added feature toggler for Log Viewer and Installer[br /]
            - Display build expiry and funding campaign notices only in the main settings[br /]
            - Replace “Remove all rules” with a primary button[br /]
            - Input boxes are focused by default[br /]
            - For numeric inputs, only the numeric keyboard is displayed[br /]
            - Input texts aren't added to the user suggestions.
        </note>
        <improve>Pair ADB via notification</improve>
        <improve>Renamed “Layout orientation” to “Layout direction”</improve>
        <improve>Use dual-pane layout for large displays</improve>
        <fix>Avoided displaying “Imported” for Watt and Blocker when nothing is selected</fix>
        <fix>
            Check if the selected directory is actually a directory before attempting to import a
            backup
        </fix>
        <fix>Fixed displaying custom commands in the mode of ops page</fix>
        <fix>
            Fixed displaying wireless debugging options when App Manager is unable to enable
            Wireless Debugging
        </fix>
        <fix>Fixed navigating one step back after a device configuration is changed</fix>
        <fix>Fixed saving backup options</fix>
        <fix>Fixed the title for the Mode of Ops settings page</fix>
        <fix>Prevented a crash that occurs on importing the rules if some of them are invalid</fix>

        <!-- UI -->
        <title type="medium">UI</title>
        <improve>
            Better handling of application-wide notifications including the progress of various
            operations
        </improve>
        <improve>
            Display all multi-selection options in a single row with an overflow menu at the end
        </improve>
        <improve>Display icons in popup menus</improve>
        <improve>
            Display shortcut editor before creating a shortcut along with a preview panel
        </improve>
        <improve>Draw activities around the display cutouts</improve>
        <improve>Improved layouts of popup and dropdown menus</improve>
        <improve>
            Tint combo-boxes in primary container color to match Android 12+ styles
        </improve>
        <improve>Used circular progress for initialization</improve>
        <fix>Fixed styling some popup menus</fix>

        <!-- UI Tracker -->
        <title type="medium">UI Tracker</title>
        <improve>Added the ability to drag the icon when iconified</improve>
        <improve>Added the ability to drag the window outside the visible display</improve>
        <improve>Display current activity name when possible</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            In addition to displaying the class name and its hierarchies, the window will display
            the activity name if there's is an activity (not all windows are activities). This
            requires the usage stats permission which is enforced here even if it's disabled in the
            settings. This is because this feature is meant to be used as a useful tool separated
            from the rest of the app, but with some level of integration.
        </note>
        <fix>Fixed freezing issues in certain devices (e.g., Samsung)</fix>

        <!-- Others -->
        <title>Others</title>
        <improve>Added a "manual" option in the ADB pairing dialog</improve>
        <improve>Added more network policies from Motorola devices.</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            - POLICY_REJECT_METERED[br /]
            - POLICY_REJECT_BACKGROUND[br /]
            - POLICY_REJECT_ALL
        </note>
        <improve>Allow opening an application in Android TV as well as for other users</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            This feature does not work in the installation completion dialog or notification.
        </note>
        <improve>Allow the remote server to run under any privileged UID</improve>
        <improve>Automatically grant usage stats permission in privileged mode</improve>
        <note subtext="true">The feature, as usual, can be disabled in settings.</note>
        <improve title="Code viewer">
            Enabled Smali to Java conversion feature in Android Nougat and earlier
        </improve>
        <improve>
            Enabled backing up data from App Manager via Android-default backup systems
        </improve>
        <improve>Enabled creating activity shortcuts for other users</improve>
        <improve>Enabled fast scrolling in the user manual page</improve>
        <improve>Kill and recreate the remote server when it's not responding</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            In some cases, the remote server fails to broadcast its presence to App Manager.
            As a result, the connection times out, and App Manager enters into an infinite
            loop of automatic troubleshooting. To break this infinite loop, App Manager will
            now kill the remote server and recreate it. This effectively guarantees
            that App Manager will never fall into an infinite loop due to an unresponsive
            server (it will, at best, take less than two minutes), and it will never require
            more than two attempts to fix such an issue by a user.
        </note>
        <improve>Made notification permission optional</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Although denying notification permission will render many features useless, it is made
            optional for those who insists on denying it. However, the permission shall still be
            asked everytime the app is launched until it times out.
        </note>
        <improve>Replaced the usernames “Main” and “Work” with “This” and “Other”</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            In no-root mode, usernames cannot be fetched from the system. Hence, “Main” and “Work”
            are inferred based on the status of the system. However, this can cause issues if the
            app is installed in the Work profile. Instead, the names “This” and “Other” are used to
            clarify the situation.
        </note>
        <improve>
            Schedule cache cleaning job more actively to ensure App Manager's caches are cleared regularly
        </improve>
        <improve>Updated documentation to reflect latest changes</improve>
        <note subtext="true">In addition, Oxygen OS specific ADB instructions were added.</note>
        <improve>Use definite mode of operation</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            When the mode of operation is set to auto, App Manager will attempt to find the best mode and set it as the
            current mode instead of “Auto” in order to improve the startup time as well as allow stable access of
            service via upcoming App Manager SDK.
        </note>
        <improve>
            Use granted permissions rather than the mode of operation to check the eligibility of a feature
        </improve>
        <improve>Use grid layout in the large displays</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            It uses an empirically derived 450dp column width allowing each column to expand from
            450dp to 2x450dp before adding a new grid.
        </note>
        <improve>Use marquee texts in suggestions/dropdown menu</improve>
        <improve>Use outlines for color codes</improve>
        <improve>Use wakelocks in long-running tasks to keep the CPU awake</improve>

        <fix title="ADB">Hide managed users which have debugging restrictions enabled</fix>
        <fix>Avoided fetching packages for other users if there's no permission to do so</fix>
        <fix>Fixed blocking components in Android 14</fix>
        <fix>Fixed blocking providers when only IFW is set</fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            Intent Firewall (IFW) does not support blocking providers. So, when IFW-only mode was
            enabled, it tried to apply only the IFW rules which resulted in the providers remaining
            unblocked. From now on, the providers are blocked via “disable” option.
        </note>
        <fix>Fixed deleting the cached application after the installation attempt fails</fix>
        <fix>Fixed delivering changes made via batch operations</fix>
        <fix>Fixed issues with executing automated tasks from the third-party applications</fix>
        <fix>Fixed launching private activities from shortcuts</fix>
        <fix>Fixed launching remote services in One Plus devices</fix>
        <fix>Fixed parsing APK files with wrong headers</fix>
        <fix>Fixed parsing the manifest of some apps</fix>
        <fix>Fixed retrieving the list of packages in some devices</fix>
        <fix>Fixed retrieving and updating permission flags in Android 12 onwards</fix>
        <fix>Fixed retrieving list of packages in some devices</fix>
        <fix>Fixed unresponsive continue button in build expiry dialog</fix>
        <fix>Fixed various security issues related to JADX</fix>
        <fix>Made setting UID/GID optional while extracting a tar archive</fix>

        <note>
            [br /][b]Full list of changes:[/b] [a
            href="https://github.com/MuntashirAkon/AppManager/compare/v3.1.0...v4.0.0"]v3.1.0...v4.0.0[/a]
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v3.1.0"
        code="423"
        date="25 March 2023">
        <new>Target Android 13</new>
        <new>Added monochrome icon for Android 13</new>
        <new>New languages: Korean, Romanian</new>
        <new>Added notice for the funding campaign</new>
        <new>Set an expiry date for each release</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            To ensure the safety of the users, App Manager is set to expire several months after it is published. A
            warning shall be issued for a certain period before the expiry date. After that, App Manager shall
            completely stop responding to any requests and prompt user to update or uninstall the application. However,
            for stable releases, it will still be possible to use the application but the warning shall be displayed
            every time the application is launched.
        </note>
        <new>Added support for v3.1 signing scheme</new>
        <new>
            Export APKS using the new [a href="https://github.com/MuntashirAkon/AppManager/discussions/358"]APKS
            specification[/a]. This is still in pre-alpha stage.
        </new>
        <improve title="Security">Removed default signing key</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Default signing key was publicly available and could have be used by others to distribute malware. Instead,
            enabling APK signing before installing an app now requires a signing key to be added (which can be either
            generated or imported).
        </note>
        <improve>Enabled searching in various selection dialogs</improve>
        <improve>
            Improved cache management in the app by periodically cleaning the obsolete files from the cache
        </improve>
        <improve>Removed the necessity of [tt].tmp[/tt] directory</improve>
        <improve>Resolve OID names of the X509 certificates</improve>
        <improve>Display inferred mode of operation in the crash logs</improve>
        <improve>Check whether Binder transaction is supported in root mode before initiating a connection</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Certain superuser implementations did not enable communications through Binder (that, is binder
            transactions) from user applications. A check has been added to ensure that the currently used superuser
            supports such communications before attempting to create a remote service.
        </note>
        <improve>Fall back to ADB if root mode is not supported</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            If App Manager cannot connect using root, root itself is used to start ADB over TCP and connect to it. This
            is also useful for certain rooting solutions which do not support Binder transactions.
        </note>
        <improve>Handle multiple users including work profile in no-root mode</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Apps in the work profile can be opened in the App Details page. They can also be launched, uninstalled, and
            the corresponding settings page can also be opened in no-root mode.
        </note>
        <improve>Ensured forward-compatibility in app ops</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            App Manager now handles vendor-specific app ops, newly added app ops in the AOSP, etc. automatically to
            prevent random crashes.
        </note>
        <improve>Improved Java to Smali conversion mechanism</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Now all the Smali files related to the current file (inner classes, for example) are also converted into
            Java to make it easier to understand the code.
        </note>
        <improve>Handle incomplete USB debugging</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            On certain devices, enabling USB debugging may not be enough to use ADB. In such cases, App Manager will
            report incomplete USB debugging along with a potential way to solve the issue.
        </note>
        <improve>Ensure the existence of shared cache directory before launching App Manager</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Shared cache directory must exist in all Android devices. If it does not, the ROM is likely broken.
        </note>
        <improve>Fall back to root mode while reading the APK file</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Some applications erroneously provide private files that aren't accessible to any installer other than the
            system ones. Therefore, root mode is used to read those files if available.
        </note>
        <improve>Handled the Internet permission in Graphene OS</improve>
        <improve>Replaced SLF4J dependency with Android compatible classes</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers and libraries</improve>
        <fix title="Profile page">Fixed crashes in the log viewer tab</fix>
        <fix>Prevented a crash in the log viewer page</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashes by avoiding the deletion of channels of the ongoing notifications</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashing if the resource string to be parsed is ill-formatted</fix>
        <fix>Fixed loading/storing URI grants (SAF) in Android 12 and later</fix>
        <fix title="TV">Fixed cropping the banner icon</fix>
        <fix>Fixed the startup progress dialog from displaying indefinitely</fix>
        <fix>Fixed issues with bottom sheet dialogs</fix>
        <fix>Fixed various theming issues</fix>
        <fix>Fixed retrieving usage stats in no-root mode</fix>
        <fix>Fixed some broken features (e.g. MagiskHide, DenyList) due to I/O errors in libsu</fix>
        <fix>Fixed SSAID not working in Android 12 and later</fix>
        <fix>Fixed connecting to ADB immediately after pairing</fix>
        <fix>Fixed various memory leaks</fix>

        <!-- Activity Interceptor page -->
        <title type="medium">Activity Interceptor page</title>
        <new>Added option to copy as [tt]am[/tt] command</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            [tt]am[/tt] (short for activity manager) or [tt]cmd activity[/tt] (Android 9 and later) can be used to start
            an activity from the terminal. This option let user copy the Intent as an [tt]am[/tt] command so that the
            same Intent can be invoked in the terminal. But not all extras are supported, only the supported extras are
            copied during the operation.
        </note>
        <fix>Fixed crashing in Motorola devices</fix>

        <!-- App Details page -->
        <title type="medium">App Details page</title>
        <new title="App Info tab">New tag: WX</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            WX tag is displayed in Android 10 and later if the application targets Android 9 or earlier. It indicates
            [a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/W%5EX"]W^X[/a] violation which allows the app to execute arbitrary
            executable files either by the modification of executables embedded within the app or by downloading them
            from the Internet.
        </note>
        <new title="App Info tab">Added option to install an existing app in another profile</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            A new menu item, namely “Install for…” is added in the three-dots menu which allows a privileged user to
            quickly install the same app in another profile without performing a complete installation.
        </note>
        <improve>Hide tips forever if close button is clicked</improve>
        <improve>Try [tt]vacuum[/tt]-ing the databases before displaying the open with dialog</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            To improve speed, databases are often stored in multiple files. Therefore, simply opening the main database
            may not cover all the data in the database. By [tt]vacuum[/tt]-ing the database, all the files are merged
            into a single database file, thereby, preventing any consistency issues.
        </note>
        <improve>Used monospace font in SSAID fields</improve>
        <improve>Display app distribution source if available in the signatures tab</improve>
        <note subtext="true">Currently, the only known source is Google Play.</note>
        <improve>Added more directories to look for systemless installations in Magisk</improve>
        <fix>Fixed permission toggles in the uses permissions tab</fix>
        <fix>Disabled launch buttons in the component tabs if the app is frozen</fix>
        <fix>Fixed links not working in Play App Signing dialog</fix>
        <improve>Display invalid native libraries in the Shared libs tab</improve>
        <improve>Replaced block/unblock button with material switch</improve>
        <fix>
            Display failure message instead of crashing if a service cannot be launched from the Services tab
        </fix>
        <fix>Prevented the app from crashing on attempting to grant GET_APP_OPS_STATS permission</fix>
        <fix>Fixed a crash on specifying an invalid icon resource in the edit shortcut dialog</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashes in the Shared Libs tab</fix>
        <fix>Fixed shortcut creation issues in some launchers</fix>
        <fix>Prevented a crash in the ADB mode which used to occur on attempting to fetch application data size</fix>
        <fix>Fixed issues with setting a custom SSAID</fix>

        <!-- Backup -->
        <title type="medium">Backup</title>
        <new>Added support for elliptic-curve cryptography (ECC)</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            ECC in App Manager uses curve 25519 with ECDH which is wrapped with SHA512withECDSA when storing the key in
            the Bouncy Castle KeyStore.
        </note>
        <new>Backup metadata version updated to 4</new>
        <improve>Use 128 bit tag size for AES encryption</improve>
        <improve>Prevented backing up the [tt]android[/tt] package</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            This particular package is the heart of Android and shouldn't be backed up or restored.
        </note>
        <fix>Use [tt]/data/media[/tt] instead of [tt]/storage/emulated[/tt] for other users</fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            In the newer versions of Android, [tt]/storage/emulated[/tt] directories belonging to another user (say, a
            work profile) cannot be accessed even with root. However, [tt]/data/media[/tt] is only accessible with root.
            Therefore, the later directory is used instead.
        </note>
        <fix>Fixed restoring backed up apps in no-root mode</fix>
        <fix>Fixed extracting backups if the directory to be created already exists</fix>
        <fix>Fixed encryption/decryption for AES 128</fix>
        <fix>Fixed a crash if no backup is selected but restore is clicked</fix>
        <fix>Fixed an issue with saving the PGP encrypted files</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashing if a storage media does not have a label</fix>
        <fix>Fixed restoring backups for other users</fix>
        <fix>Fixed scrolling issues in backup/restore dialog</fix>

        <!-- Explorer page -->
        <title type="medium">Explorer page</title>
        <new>Added list options containing various sorting and folder options</new>
        <new>Allowed opening [b]jar[/b] and [b]dex[/b] files</new>

        <!-- Freeze/unfreeze -->
        <title type="medium">Freeze/unfreeze</title>
        <new>Replaced enable/disable with freeze/unfreeze</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            Freeze/unfreeze can be [a href="app-manager://settings/rules_prefs/freeze_type"]customised[/a] to disable,
            suspend or hide the applications instead of only disabling it. The colour codes used for disabling is used
            for freezing.
        </note>
        <new>Added freeze/unfreeze toggle shortcut in the App Info tab</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            Long clicking on the freeze or unfreeze buttons in the App Info tab opens a dialog where how the shortcut
            shall work apart from freezing/unfreezing can be configured. If a shortcut already exists, the existing
            shortcut shall be updated.[br /]
            It offers the following options:[br /]
            1. Open application after unfreezing it[br /]
            2. Open application (requires 1 to be enabled) but without an entry in Recents[br /]
            3. Refreeze the application when the phone is locked.[br /]
            When “open after unfreezing” flag is enabled and the app isn't frozen, clicking on the freeze shortcut opens
            a dialog asking whether to freeze or open the app instead of performing a freeze.
        </note>

        <!-- Installer page -->
        <title type="medium">Installer page</title>
        <improve>Ensured all the installation confirmation notifications are different in no-root mode</improve>
        <fix>Fixed a rare crash used to occur due to the accidental closing of the installer page</fix>
        <new>
            Enabled installing an existing package without requiring a complete re-installation. Requires root/ADB
        </new>
        <improve>
            Use PackageManager API instead of the [tt]pm[/tt] command to uninstall updates of a system app
        </improve>
        <improve>Added workarounds for permission denied issues in MIUI 12.5 and later</improve>
        <fix>
            Prevented installer from running forever in no-root mode due to the mismanagement of installer queue
        </fix>
        <fix>
            Fixed installing app for all users when “all users” option is selected
        </fix>
        <fix>Prevented the installer from crashing if the activity Intent can't be opened</fix>

        <!-- Main page -->
        <title type="medium">Main page</title>
        <new title="Batch Ops">Enabled batch uninstaller in no-root mode</new>
        <new title="Batch Ops">Added an option to export app list</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            App list can be exported in either XML or Markdown format, making it easier to store or share. List exported
            in XML format may be also imported to App Manager in the future.
        </note>
        <new>New sorting options: app size, data usage, launch count, screen time, last usage time</new>
        <new>
            New filtering options: apps using Android KeyStore, apps using SAF (Storage Access Framework), apps with
            SSAID.
        </new>
        <new>Added support for [tt]market://search?q=query[/tt]</new>
        <improve title="Batch Ops">
            Remove removed items from the selection list after a previous operation is finished.
        </improve>
        <improve>Improve updating the list of applications</improve>
        <improve>Replaced “Instructions” with “User Manual”</improve>
        <fix>Fixed searching issues in non-virtual keyboard</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashing on clicking items in list options</fix>
        <fix>Fixed sorting when a profile is selected in the list options</fix>
        <fix>
            Fixed displaying backup volume unavailable messages when [tt]/sdcard/AppManager[/tt] was inaccessible or
            unavailable
        </fix>

        <!-- Running Apps page -->
        <title type="medium">Running Apps page</title>
        <new>Added searching by package name</new>
        <new>Enabled advanced searching</new>
        <fix>Fixed double scrollbars</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashes in no-root mode while checking for [tt]RUN_IN_BACKGROUND[/tt]</fix>
        <fix>Fixed [tt]/proc/$PID/stat[/tt] parsing bug</fix>

        <!-- Scanner page -->
        <improve>Avoid scanning nested classes to improve the performance of the scanner</improve>
        <fix>Fixed a rare crash used to occur when the activity is accidentally closed</fix>

        <!-- Settings page -->
        <new>
            Added [a href="app-manager://settings/appearance_prefs/enabled_features"]option[/a] to disable opening App
            Info page from the third-party applications
        </new>
        <fix>Disabled wireless debugging, not ADB over TCP in API &lt; 30</fix>
        <fix>Fixed setting default log level in log viewer preferences</fix>

        <!-- UI -->
        <title type="medium">UI</title>
        <improve>Migrated to Material 3-style preferences</improve>
        <improve>Prevented closing multi-selection panel after starting an operation</improve>
        <improve>Replaced MD2 (Material Design 2) switches with M3 (Material 3) switches</improve>
        <improve>Removed dark theme hacks for the WebView in the help page</improve>
        <fix>Fixed icon theming issues in Android 12</fix>
        <fix>Fixed loading dynamic colours in the splash screen</fix>

        <note>
            [br /][b]Full list of changes:[/b] [a
            href="https://github.com/MuntashirAkon/AppManager/compare/v3.0.0...v3.1.0"]v3.0.0...v3.1.0[/a]
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v3.0.0"
        code="410"
        date="4 August 2022">
        <note subtext="true">
            Credit goes to [a href="https://github.com/PookaMustard"]Pooka Mustard[/a] for compiling the release notes
            from an incredible number of commits.
        </note>
        <new>
            [b]App Explorer.[/b] It can be used to view and open the internal file structure of an APK. It is visible
            when opening an APK using an external application such as a file explorer. This option can be disabled in [a
            href="app-manager://settings/appearance_prefs/enabled_features"]settings[/a].
        </new>
        <new>
            [b]VirusTotal.[/b] Added ability to fetch reports from and send APK files to VirusTotal, using an API key
            obtained from [a href="https://virustotal.com"]https://virustotal.com[/a]. To use the feature, the
            [a href="app-manager://settings/appearance_prefs/enabled_features"]Internet feature[/a] must be enabled and
            the API key must be [a href="app-manager://settings/vt_apikey"]inserted[/a]
        </new>

        <!-- Main page -->
        <title type="medium">Main page</title>
        <new>Add sort by [i]installation date[/i]</new>
        <new title="Batch Ops">New batch operations such as clearing cache, controlling net policies</new>
        <improve>Enabled [i]Running apps[/i] filter in no-root mode</improve>
        <improve>Reduced waiting time for updating the app list</improve>
        <improve title="Batch Ops">
            The logs from the last batch operation can be viewed or copied if it fails
        </improve>
        <improve title="Batch Ops">
            Hide actions in the multi-selection view if the screen height of App Manager is too small. Actions can be
            revealed by tapping the selected-apps counter in the top-middle part of the view
        </improve>
        <improve title="Batch Ops">Enable only the actions that can be executed based on the selected apps</improve>
        <fix>Fixed incomplete list of applications</fix>
        <fix>Fixed listing running applications if they are running in different processes</fix>

        <!-- App Details page -->
        <title type="medium">App Details page</title>
        <new title="Services tab">Added a launch button to launch a service</new>
        <improve title="Components tab">
            Enabled advanced component blocking, accessible by long clicking on the block/unblock button
        </improve>
        <improve title="Components tab">Display process name</improve>
        <improve title="Activities tab">
            Merged two shortcut buttons into one button, namely [i]Create Shortcut[/i], and add a new button, namely
            [i]launch[/i] button to launch the activities
        </improve>
        <improve title="Activities tab">Enabled opening non-exported activities via Activity Interceptor</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            To open an activity in the Activity Interceptor, long click on the [i]Launch[/i] button.
        </note>
        <improve title="Shared Libraries tab">
            Display library description including its file type such as shared object, executable, jar or APK
        </improve>
        <improve title="Permissions tab">Display external permissions required by an app</improve>
        <fix title="Uses Permissions tab">Fixed displaying unsupported or unused permissions</fix>
        <fix title="Signatures tab">Fixed retrieving signing info in older Android versions</fix>

        <!-- App Info tab -->
        <title type="small">App Info tab</title>
        <new>Display primary ABI, hidden API and SELinux info</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            Hidden APIs are the methods and classes deliberately hidden by the OS (since Android Pie) and are
            inaccessible to any third-party applications by default.
        </note>
        <new>Added [i]Play App Signing[/i] tag</new>
        <improve>
            Tapping any entry in the dialog accessible from the [i]running[/i] tag opens the Log Viewer page with the
            process ID (PID) of the selected service filtered by deault.
        </improve>
        <improve>Display [i]Trackers[/i] in green if all the trackers are blocked</improve>
        <note subtext="true">The associated dialog also marks all the blocked trackers in green.</note>
        <improve>Display warning if the user attempts to disable App Manager</improve>
        <improve>Enabled editing the SSAID field</improve>
        <improve>Display [i]View in Settings[/i] as an action in no-root mode</improve>
        <improve>Action buttons match Android 12-style</improve>
        <fix>Fixed displaying app info of an APK without a valid signature</fix>
        <fix>Fixed clearing caches in Android 7.1 and older in ADB mode</fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            In Android Marshmallow and Nougat, the only way to clear cache is to list all the applications then clear
            their caches individually.
        </note>

        <!-- Profile -->
        <title type="medium">Profile</title>
        <new>
            Added the ability to trigger profiles via third-party apps such as
            [a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/com.jens.automation2/"]Automation[/a] or Tasker.
            See [a href="https://muntashirakon.github.io/AppManager/#sec:automating-tasks"]docs[/a] for details
        </new>
        <fix>Fixed displaying apps from all users</fix>
        <fix>Prevented adding duplicate application items</fix>
        <fix>Fixed displaying apps from all users</fix>

        <!-- Backup/Restore -->
        <title type="medium">Backup/Restore</title>
        <new>
            Ability to import backups from old or discontinued applications such as Titanium Backup, OAndBackup and
            Swift Backup (version 3.0–3.2)
        </new>
        <improve>
            Backup/restore MagiskHide and Magisk DenyList rules. If MagiskHide rule is detected but only Magisk DenyList
            is present, it will fall back to Magisk DenyList
        </improve>
        <improve>Restore last modification time</improve>
        <improve>Display backup date in the backup info</improve>
        <improve>Improved backup speed by removing recursive functions</improve>
        <improve>
            Improved backup/restore dialog to include separate tabs for backup and restore as well as the options to
            freeze or unfreeze a backup
        </improve>
        <improve>Force select [i]APK files[/i] option in the restore tab if the apps aren't installed</improve>
        <fix>Fixed restoring backups with KeyStore</fix>
        <note subtext="true">Restoring KeyStore backups may not work if they are restored in a different device.</note>

        <!-- Activity Interceptor page -->
        <title type="medium">Activity Interceptor page</title>
        <new>Added option to create shortcuts and copy-and-paste contents</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            The copied text contains [tt]tab[/tt] separated entries. So, directly pasting them to messaging platforms
            may not work.
        </note>
        <new>Added [i]class[/i], [i]package[/i] and [i]identifier[/i] fields</new>
        <new>Added option to resolve and open activities using root</new>

        <!-- Running Apps page -->
        <title type="medium">Running Apps page</title>
        <new>Display memory (RAM) and swap information on top of the page</new>
        <new>
            View the details of a process by clicking on the item. For Android packages, the relevant App Info page
            can be accessed by tapping the [i]info[/i] button in the top-right corner of the sheet
        </new>
        <fix>Fixed detecting running apps with zygote preload</fix>

        <!-- Installer -->
        <title type="medium">Installer</title>
        <new>
            Added [i]App Info[/i] button in the top-right corner of the installation-completed dialog, which opens the
            App Details page
        </new>
        <improve>Added the ability to install multiple applications by maintaining a queue</improve>
        <improve>
            In Android 12 and later, applications previous installed with App Manager can be updated without any user
            interactions in the no-root mode
        </improve>
        <improve>Added the option to downgrade apps in the no-root mode</improve>
        <improve>Improved how splits are selected during installation</improve>
        <fix>Prevented the installer from hanging forever in the Knox-enabled Samsung devices</fix>
        <fix>Fixed support for applications uninstalled without clearing data</fix>
        <fix>Fixed handling applications with proof-of-rotation</fix>
        <fix>Fixed extracting OBB files</fix>

        <!-- Settings page -->
        <title type="medium">Settings</title>
        <new>
            Added [a href="app-manager://settings/advanced_prefs/saved_apk_format"]the option[/a] to specify a format
            for the APK files saved using batch operations or profiles
        </new>
        <new>
            Added [a href="app-manager://settings/advanced_prefs/selected_users"]the option[/a] to select the users App
            Manager should work with if the device has multiple users
        </new>
        <new>
            Added [a href="app-manager://settings/installer"]an option[/a] to block trackers immediately after
            installing an application if it is installed with App Manager's installer
        </new>
        <new>
            Added the option to select a [a href="app-manager://settings/rules_prefs/default_blocking_method"]default
            blocking method[/a]
        </new>
        <new>
            Added an option to reload apps in the [i]Troubleshooting[/i] category
        </new>
        <improve>
            Added [a href="app-manager://settings/installer"]the ability[/a] to install apps in the background
        </improve>
        <improve>Implement the new-style changelog</improve>
        <improve>Fallback to no-root mode if root or ADB is not detected.</improve>
        <improve>
            Full implementation of wireless debugging. See [a
            href="https://muntashirakon.github.io/AppManager/#sec:wireless-debugging"]docs[/a] for details
        </improve>
        <improve>Improved auto-detection of ADB</improve>
        <fix>Fixed changing application locale</fix>
        <fix>
            Fixed compatibility issues preventing pre-Marshmallow devices from displaying the [i]About the Device[/i]
            page
        </fix>
        <fix>Fixed importing keys from PKCS12 KeyStore file</fix>
        <fix>Fixed generating RSA keypair in Android Lollipop</fix>

        <!-- Others -->
        <title type="medium">Others</title>
        <new title="UI">Material 3 and dynamic colours</new>
        <new title="UI">
            Advanced searching and filtering, including the option to search by suffix, prefix or the regular
            expressions
        </new>
        <new title="1-Click Ops page">
            Added [i]Trim caches in all apps[/i] operation, which deletes the cache files of all applications, including
            Android system applications
        </new>
        <new title="Widget">A widget to help clear caches in all applications as in the 1-click ops page</new>
        <new title="Widget">
            A Digital Wellbeing-style widget with three resize options that displays the screen time along with the
            three mostly used applications
        </new>
        <new title="Documentation">New style single-page documentation</new>
        <new title="Language">Added Indonesian and Italian</new>
        <note subtext="true">Removed Bengali due to lack of translators.</note>
        <new title="Shared Preferences Editor">Added support for [tt]set[/tt] data</new>
        <new title="Profile page">
            Added [i]log viewer[/i] section where logs from the past profile triggers are displayed
        </new>
        <new title="Log Viewer">
            Changed extension of saved logs from [tt].log[/tt] to [tt].am.log[/tt] which can be opened in App Manager
            from the external apps or the system's [i]Sharing[/i] feature
        </new>
        <new title="Magisk">Added support for Magisk DenyList rules.</new>
        <new title="Magisk">Multi-process support for MagiskHide and Magisk DenyList</new>

        <improve title="App Usage page">Improved app usage details dialog to include more usage information</improve>
        <improve title="App Usage page">
            Data usage for mobile and Wi-Fi networks are shown with the Android phone and Wi-Fi icons respectively
            instead of the 'M' and 'W' prefixes
        </improve>
        <improve title="Documentation">Redirect to the docs site in case the WebView is unavailable</improve>
        <improve title="UI">
            Added Fast-scroller in the app info tab, the Running Apps page, the App Usage page and in the Manifest/Code
            Viewer page
        </improve>
        <improve title="UI">
            Key generator, changelog and about dialogs in the settings page are displayed in full-screen on small
            screens
        </improve>
        <improve title="Security">Use TLS 1.3 for connecting to ADB in Android 9 and later</improve>
        <improve title="Shared Preferences Editor">Display exit prompt if the file was edited</improve>
        <improve title="Scanner page">Display [tt].smali[/tt] content and a preview of its [tt].java[/tt] file</improve>
        <improve title="Scanner page">Renamed [i]Source Directory[/i] to [i]APK Checksums[/i]</improve>
        <improve title="Log Viewer">
            Clicking the settings menu opens the Log Viewer settings instead of the general settings page
        </improve>
        <improve title="Log Viewer">Replaced [b]Save Partial[/b] with multi-selection mode</improve>
        <improve title="UX">Improved navigating the app using a keyboard or a TV remote</improve>
        <improve title="Manifest Viewer">Reduced font-size to improve readability</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers and libraries</improve>

        <fix title="Manifest Viewer">Fixed displaying certain manifest files</fix>
        <fix title="Documentation">Fixed [i]File not found[/i] issue in some versions of Android</fix>
        <fix title="Language">Fixed punctuation issues in French</fix>
        <fix title="UI">Fix prominent RTL layout issues</fix>
        <fix>App Manager files are now cached in the cache directory instead of data directory</fix>
        <fix>fixed checking for root in some devices</fix>
        <fix>Fixed granting or revoking some app ops and permissions</fix>
        <fix>Fixed restoring application permissions while applying rules or restoring backups</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashes on attempting to disable net policies for the core applications</fix>

        <note>
            [br /][b]Full list of changes:[/b] [a
            href="https://github.com/MuntashirAkon/AppManager/compare/c504b30...v3.0.0"]v2.6.0...v3.0.0[/a]
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v2.6.0"
        code="385"
        date="25 Apr 2021">
        <new>
            [b]New Feature:[/b] Log Viewer (accessible from the main menu, “running” tag in the app info page and
            three-dots menu in each item of the running apps page).
        </new>
        <new>[b]New language:[/b] Arabic</new>
        <new>Added AES and RSA encryption (AES/GCM/NoPadding with 12 bytes IV) for backups</new>
        <new>Added clear cache option in ADB mode</new>
        <new>Added filter by profile in the main page</new>
        <new>Added options to disable log viewer</new>
        <new>
            Added the ability to import (JKS, BKS and PKCS #12 KeyStores and PK8 formatted private key and PEM
            certificate) and generate signing keys
        </new>
        <new>
            Added the option to import/export App Manager's KeyStore. It's a typical Bouncy Castle KeyStore in BKS
            extension
        </new>
        <new>
            Added SAF tag in the app info page for apps that uses storage access framework. Clicking on it lists the
            granted URIs.
        </new>
        <new>
            Added [b]Verify and redo backups[/b] and [b]back up apps with changes[/b] in 1-click ops page (in the backup
            section)
        </new>
        <improve>
            Removed UnAPKM from the app as newer APKMs are no longer encrypted. (Use UnAPKM extension from F-Droid to
            continue to decrypt the encrypted APKM files.)
        </improve>
        <improve>Added compatibility support for mobile data usage in old operating systems</improve>
        <improve>
            Added colour codes to the “backup” tag in the main page denoting the age of the backups: Red => Uninstalled,
            Dark cyan => Up to date backup, Orange => Outdated backup
        </improve>
        <improve>Added select all button in various multiple choice dialogs</improve>
        <improve>Display native libraries alongside shared libraries in the shared libs tab</improve>
        <improve>Display file names that could not be imported (when importing files from Blocker or Watt)</improve>
        <improve>Improved formatting of the backup info dialogs</improve>
        <improve>Moved usage access to enable/disable features in the settings page</improve>
        <improve>Organized settings by moving a rules and installer settings to a different fragment</improve>
        <improve>Replaced block trackers with block/unblock trackers</improve>
        <improve>Store backup hashes in the database to detect changes in data (will be enhanced in future)</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers and libraries</improve>
        <fix>Renamed global component blocking to instant component blocking</fix>
        <fix>Renamed [b]Backup APK[/b] to [b]Save APK[/b]</fix>
        <fix>Removed the backup option [b]Source[/b] and renamed [b]APK only[/b] to [b]APK files[/b]</fix>
        <fix>
            Replaced the backup option [b]Data[/b] with [b]Internal data[/b]. [b]External data[/b] no longer depends on
            this option
        </fix>
        <fix>Replaced the backup option [b]Exclude cache[/b] with [b]Cache[/b] (i.e., the flag has been inverted).</fix>
        <fix>Avoided crash in the app details page when device configuration (night mode, orientation, etc.) changes
        </fix>
        <fix>Backup URI grants only for the given users</fix>
        <fix>Fixed a crash occurs occasionally when detecting whether an app is running</fix>
        <fix>Fixed a crash when yesterday data isn't available in the app usage page</fix>
        <fix>
            Fixed a crash when back button is pressed immediately after pressing the add button in the profile page
        </fix>
        <fix>Fixed backup service from hanging if it encounters invalid file types</fix>
        <fix>Fixed fetching storage info for users other than the current user</fix>
        <fix>Fixed hidden API restriction bypass issue for Android 11 (which unfortunately increased the APK size)</fix>
        <fix>Fixed displaying wrong data usage in Android Lollipop devices</fix>
        <fix>Fixed restoring backups with symbolic links</fix>
        <fix>Foreground service notification is removed immediately after the operation is complete</fix>
        <note>
            [b]Notice:[/b] After restoring apps that use SAF and SSAID, the device has to be restarted immediately.
            Currently, the users are not notified if a restart is necessary after restoring a backup.
            If you are in confusion, make sure to restart your device after restoring a backup.
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="pre-release"
        version="v2.5.24"
        code="383"
        date="21 Mar 2021">
        <new>New language: Tradition Chinese</new>
        <new>Added filter by uninstalled apps, apps without backups in the main page</new>
        <new>Allow specifying custom installer package which may or may not be installed</new>
        <new>Copy package name on clicking on the package name in the app info tab</new>
        <new>Display file size, requirement, etc. for split APKs in the APK selection dialog</new>
        <new>Display version and tracker info in the installation confirmation dialog</new>
        <improve>
            Added wildcard support for app ops and permissions for profiles. [tt]*[/tt] can be used instead of
            specifying app ops or permissions to revoke all configured/dangerous permissions/app ops
        </improve>
        <improve>App icons are cached to improve load time</improve>
        <improve>Complete rewrite of running apps internals in Java</improve>
        <improve>Display uninstalled system apps and display installation prompt on clicking them</improve>
        <improve>Improved ADB detection and persistence of such detection</improve>
        <improve>Removed toybox along with its dependencies</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers and libraries</improve>
        <improve>Utilise multiple CPUs for back up/restore</improve>
        <improve>
            Verify copied checksum with the checksum of the signing certificate of the app on clicking on the app icon
            in the app info page
        </improve>
        <fix>Added additional verifications to ensure that screen lock is not bypassed</fix>
        <fix>Fixed back up/restore failure on some Android devices</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashes in the app details page when system configuration changes</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crash on creating shortcuts on devices that do not support pin shortcut</fix>
        <fix>Fixed generating wrong checksum for certificates in the signatures tab</fix>
        <fix>Fixed uninstalling app for multiple users</fix>
        <fix>Fixed various crashes on opening APK files from external apps</fix>
        <fix>Hide backup option if one of the selected apps is not installed</fix>
        <fix>Verify KeyStore backups during restoring a backup</fix>
    </release>
    <release
        type="pre-release"
        version="v2.5.23"
        code="381"
        date="4 Feb 2021">
        <new>Added screen lock</new>
        <new>Added [b]Add to profile[/b] in the batch ops and app info tab</new>
        <new>Added enable/disable features in settings (replacing interceptor setting)</new>
        <new>Added leanback launcher support with banner (Android TV)</new>
        <new>Backup/restore SSAID (requires immediate restart)</new>
        <new>Backup APK in external SD card</new>
        <new>
            AppInfo: Added options to configure battery optimization, net policy, SSAID. For each of them, tag clouds
            will be displayed if the values are not default.
        </new>
        <new>Interceptor: add/remove extras</new>
        <new>Made settings page accessible from Android Settings</new>
        <new>
            Main: Added filter by installed app, sort by number of trackers and last actions (the latter is not stable
            yet)
        </new>
        <new>New language: Japanese</new>
        <new>Search using app initials in the main page (e.g. TS will list TrebleShot in the search results)</new>
        <new>Use of database as a middle man to improve load time</new>
        <improve>AppInfo: Added options to select tracker components to block/unblock</improve>
        <improve>Improved backup volume selection</improve>
        <improve>
            Main: Batch selection on long click after the selection mode is turned on (i.e. selection mode is turned on
            if you click on any app icon or long click on any app)
        </improve>
        <improve>Main: Replaced sort and filter with list options</improve>
        <improve>Main: Set [b]backup[/b] to red if the app is not installed</improve>
        <improve>Removed F-Droid, Aurora Droid in favour of F-Droid links (to support user preferred clients)</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers, libraries, profile presets</improve>
        <fix>Fixed app icon (it now matches app theme)</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crash while blocking app components of a recently updated app</fix>
        <fix>Fixed various crashes in the app info tab</fix>
        <fix>Properly sanitize profile names and exported APK(S) file names</fix>
        <fix>Remove rules for all users (rather than the current user) in settings</fix>
        <fix>Replaced AppManager/tmp with AppManager/.tmp</fix>
        <fix>Replaced image buttons with material buttons (fixes crash when using Substratum themes)</fix>
        <note>
            Don't set folders inside [tt]/mnt/media_rw/[/tt] as the backup volume. It doesn't work for backup/restore.
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="pre-release"
        version="v2.5.22"
        code="379"
        date="16 Jan 20201">
        <new>1-Click Ops: add backup/restore options</new>
        <new>Added the ability to freeze backup (by creating [tt].freeze[/tt] in the corresponding backup)</new>
        <new>Added option to enable/disable MagiskHide in the App Info tab (enable option in the overflow menu)</new>
        <new>Added option to enable/disable interceptor (in settings)</new>
        <new>Added option to launch services</new>
        <new>Added option to select backup volume</new>
        <new>Backup/restore app installer, netpolicy, deviceidle, magiskhide and notification access</new>
        <new>Backup/restore URI grants (need immediate reboot after the restore)</new>
        <new>Grant/revoke permissions in profile</new>
        <new>New attribute in backup/restore: size</new>
        <new>New attribute in profile: users</new>
        <new>New tag in App Info: backups</new>
        <improve>Added encryption info in about device</improve>
        <improve>Block and disable components using IFW and PackageManager respectively for maximum protection</improve>
        <improve>Improved instructions in the 1-Click Ops page</improve>
        <improve>Integrated docs within AM as a dynamic feature</improve>
        <improve>Open DRM-free APKM files without conversion</improve>
        <improve>Sort apps by labels, display user/system tag in the profile page</improve>
        <improve>Replace backup all users with custom users</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers and libraries</improve>
        <improve>
            Remove [tt]FLAG_ACTIVITY_FORWARD_RESULT[/tt] from list of flags (if present) in the interceptor
        </improve>
        <fix>Add [tt].nomedia[/tt] file in the backup folder</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crash on clicking [i]about device[/i] item in Settings</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crash in the profile page</fix>
        <fix>Fixed compatibility issue of IFW in Android M or prior versions</fix>
        <fix>Get correct user ID before performing uninstall</fix>
        <fix>Migrate to PackageManager API instead of using unreliable pm command</fix>
        <fix>Update theme name on changing app theme</fix>
        <fix>Use package name from metadata instead of directory name for backups</fix>
        <note>
            Backup/restore feature is now beta. From now on, backward compatibility for backup/restorer will be
            provided.
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="pre-release"
        version="v2.5.21"
        code="377"
        date="1 Jan 2021">
        <new>New language: Farsi</new>
        <new>Added about device in the settings page</new>
        <new>Added an installation button in the scanner page for the external APK files</new>
        <new>Added the option to set custom app ops and modes in the three-dots menu</new>
        <improve>Added shortcut support for Android N MR1 or less</improve>
        <improve>Display app ops associated with the declared permissions in the app ops tab</improve>
        <improve>Display feature availability and version number in the uses features tab</improve>
        <improve>Display icon for uninstalled but backed up apps in the main page</improve>
        <improve>Display tracker count in a new line instead of under brackets in the 1-click ops page</improve>
        <improve>Improved app install time for ADB users</improve>
        <improve>
            Renamed “deny app ops” to “set mode for app ops”, added the option to specify modes in 1-click ops page
        </improve>
        <improve>Reordered backup options along with description for each items</improve>
        <improve>Updated ADBLib</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers and libraries</improve>
        <fix>Fixed crashes of the app ops tab in Android 11</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashes of the app ops tab in MIUI</fix>
        <fix>Fixed prompting users for ADB permission repeatedly when auto is the mode of operation</fix>
        <fix>Hide launch and shortcut buttons from the activities tab for external APK</fix>
        <fix>Use both package mode and UID mode for app ops from Android 6</fix>
        <fix>Use data folder to store server/IPC related files</fix>
    </release>
</changelog>