<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><!DOCTYPE changelog [

    <!ELEMENT changelog (release+)><!ATTLIST changelog bullet CDATA #IMPLIED>

    <!ELEMENT release ((title|note|new|improve|fix)*)><!ATTLIST release type CDATA #REQUIRED><!ATTLIST release version CDATA #REQUIRED><!ATTLIST release code CDATA #REQUIRED><!ATTLIST release date CDATA #REQUIRED>

    <!ELEMENT title (#PCDATA)><!ATTLIST title type CDATA #IMPLIED>

    <!ELEMENT note (#PCDATA)><!ATTLIST note title CDATA #IMPLIED><!ATTLIST note bullet CDATA #IMPLIED><!ATTLIST note subtext CDATA #IMPLIED>

    <!ELEMENT new (#PCDATA)><!ATTLIST new title CDATA #IMPLIED><!ATTLIST new bullet CDATA #IMPLIED><!ATTLIST new subtext CDATA #IMPLIED>

    <!ELEMENT improve (#PCDATA)><!ATTLIST improve title CDATA #IMPLIED><!ATTLIST improve bullet CDATA #IMPLIED><!ATTLIST improve subtext CDATA #IMPLIED>

    <!ELEMENT fix (#PCDATA)><!ATTLIST fix title CDATA #IMPLIED><!ATTLIST fix bullet CDATA #IMPLIED><!ATTLIST fix subtext CDATA #IMPLIED>

    ]>
<changelog>
    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v3.0.3"
        code="414"
        date="24 October 2022">
        <new>Backup metadata version updated to 4</new>
        <improve>Use 128 bit tag size for AES encryption</improve>
        <fix>Fixed encryption/decryption for AES 128</fix>
        <fix>Fixed an issue with saving the PGP encrypted files</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashing if a storage media does not have a label</fix>
        <note>
            [br /][b]Full list of changes:[/b] [a
            href="https://github.com/MuntashirAkon/AppManager/compare/v3.0.2...v3.0.3"]v3.0.2...v3.0.3[/a]
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v3.0.2"
        code="413"
        date="20 September 2022">
        <improve>Removed dark theme hacks for the WebView in the help page</improve>
        <fix>Fixed loading dynamic colours in the splash screen</fix>
        <fix>Fixed shortcut creation issues in some launchers</fix>
        <fix>Prevented a crash in the ADB mode which used to occur on attempting to fetch application data size</fix>
        <fix>Prevented a nasty crash used to occur when an activity is needed to be recreated</fix>
        <note>
            [br /][b]Full list of changes:[/b] [a
            href="https://github.com/MuntashirAkon/AppManager/compare/v3.0.1...v3.0.2"]v3.0.1...v3.0.2[/a]
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v3.0.1"
        code="412"
        date="5 September 2022">
        <improve>Display inferred mode of operation in the crash logs</improve>
        <improve>Handled the Internet permission in GrapheneOS</improve>
        <improve>Prevented closing multi-selection panel after starting an operation</improve>
        <improve>Replaced MD2 (Material Design 2) switches with M3 (Material 3) switches</improve>
        <fix>Fixed icon theming issues in Android 12</fix>

        <fix title="App Details page">
            Display failure message instead of crashing if a service cannot be launched from the Services tab
        </fix>
        <fix title="App Details page">Fixed crashes in the Shared Libs tab</fix>
        <fix title="Installer">
            Fixed a rare crash used to occur due to the accidental closing of the installer page
        </fix>
        <fix title="Main page">Fixed sorting when a profile is selected in the list options</fix>
        <fix title="Main page">
            Fixed displaying backup volume unavailable messages when [tt]/sdcard/AppManager[/tt] was inaccessible or
            unavailable
        </fix>
        <fix title="Profile page">Fixed crashes in the log viewer tab</fix>
        <fix title="Running Apps page">Fixed double scrollbars</fix>
        <fix title="Running Apps page">Fixed crashes in no-root mode while checking for [tt]RUN_IN_BACKGROUND[/tt]</fix>
        <fix title="Scanner page">Fixed a rare crash used to occur when the activity is accidentally closed</fix>
        <note>
            [br /][b]Full list of changes:[/b] [a
            href="https://github.com/MuntashirAkon/AppManager/compare/v3.0.0...v3.0.1"]v3.0.0...v3.0.1[/a]
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v3.0.0"
        code="410"
        date="4 August 2022">
        <note subtext="true">
            Credit goes to [a href="https://github.com/PookaMustard"]Pooka Mustard[/a] for compiling the release notes
            from an incredible number of commits.
        </note>
        <new>
            [b]App Explorer.[/b] It can be used to view and open the internal file structure of an APK. It is visible
            when opening an APK using an external application such as a file explorer. This option can be disabled in [a
            href="app-manager://settings/enabled_features"]settings[/a].
        </new>
        <new>
            [b]VirusTotal.[/b] Added ability to fetch reports from and send APK files to VirusTotal, using an API key
            obtained from [a href="https://virustotal.com"]https://virustotal.com[/a]. To use the feature, the
            [a href="app-manager://settings/enabled_features"]Internet feature[/a] must be
            enabled and the API key must be
            [a href="app-manager://settings/vt_apikey"]inserted[/a]
        </new>

        <!-- Main page -->
        <title type="medium">Main page</title>
        <new>Add sort by [i]installation date[/i]</new>
        <new title="Batch Ops">New batch operations such as clearing cache, controlling net policies</new>
        <improve>Enabled [i]Running apps[/i] filter in no-root mode</improve>
        <improve>Reduced waiting time for updating the app list</improve>
        <improve title="Batch Ops">
            The logs from the last batch operation can be viewed or copied if it fails
        </improve>
        <improve title="Batch Ops">
            Hide actions in the multi-selection view if the screen height of App Manager is too small. Actions can be
            revealed by tapping the selected-apps counter in the top-middle part of the view
        </improve>
        <improve title="Batch Ops">Enable only the actions that can be executed based on the selected apps</improve>
        <fix>Fixed incomplete list of applications</fix>
        <fix>Fixed listing running applications if they are running in different processes</fix>

        <!-- App Details page -->
        <title type="medium">App Details page</title>
        <new title="Services tab">Added a launch button to launch a service</new>
        <improve title="Components tab">
            Enabled advanced component blocking, accessible by long clicking on the block/unblock button
        </improve>
        <improve title="Components tab">Display process name</improve>
        <improve title="Activities tab">
            Merged two shortcut buttons into one button, namely [i]Create Shortcut[/i], and add a new button, namely
            [i]launch[/i] button to launch the activities
        </improve>
        <improve title="Activities tab">Enabled opening non-exported activities via Activity Interceptor</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            To open an activity in the Activity Interceptor, long click on the [i]Launch[/i] button.
        </note>
        <improve title="Shared Libraries tab">
            Display library description including its file type such as shared object, executable, jar or APK
        </improve>
        <improve title="Permissions tab">Display external permissions required by an app</improve>
        <fix title="Uses Permissions tab">Fixed displaying unsupported or unused permissions</fix>
        <fix title="Signatures tab">Fixed retrieving signing info in older Android versions</fix>

        <!-- App Info tab -->
        <title type="small">App Info tab</title>
        <new>Display primary ABI, hidden API and SELinux info</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            Hidden APIs are the methods and classes deliberately hidden by the OS (since Android Pie) and are
            inaccessible to any third-party applications by default.
        </note>
        <new>Added [i]Play App Signing[/i] tag</new>
        <improve>
            Tapping any entry in the dialog accessible from the [i]running[/i] tag opens the Log Viewer page with the
            process ID (PID) of the selected service filtered by deault.
        </improve>
        <improve>Display [i]Trackers[/i] in green if all the trackers are blocked</improve>
        <note subtext="true">The associated dialog also marks all the blocked trackers in green.</note>
        <improve>Display warning if the user attempts to disable App Manager</improve>
        <improve>Enabled editing the SSAID field</improve>
        <improve>Display [i]View in Settings[/i] as an action in no-root mode</improve>
        <improve>Action buttons match Android 12-style</improve>
        <fix>Fixed displaying app info of an APK without a valid signature</fix>
        <fix>Fixed clearing caches in Android 7.1 and older in ADB mode</fix>
        <note subtext="true">
            In Android Marshmallow and Nougat, the only way to clear cache is to list all the applications then clear
            their caches individually.
        </note>

        <!-- Profile -->
        <title type="medium">Profile</title>
        <new>
            Added the ability to trigger profiles via third-party apps such as
            [a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/com.jens.automation2/"]Automation[/a] or Tasker.
            See [a href="https://muntashirakon.github.io/AppManager/#sec:automating-tasks"]docs[/a] for details
        </new>
        <fix>Fixed displaying apps from all users</fix>
        <fix>Prevented adding duplicate application items</fix>
        <fix>Fixed displaying apps from all users</fix>

        <!-- Backup/Restore -->
        <title type="medium">Backup/Restore</title>
        <new>
            Ability to import backups from old or discontinued applications such as Titanium Backup, OAndBackup and
            Swift Backup (version 3.0–3.2)
        </new>
        <improve>
            Backup/restore MagiskHide and Magisk DenyList rules. If MagiskHide rule is detected but only Magisk DenyList
            is present, it will fall back to Magisk DenyList
        </improve>
        <improve>Restore last modification time</improve>
        <improve>Display backup date in the backup info</improve>
        <improve>Improved backup speed by removing recursive functions</improve>
        <improve>
            Improved backup/restore dialog to include separate tabs for backup and restore as well as the options to
            freeze or unfreeze a backup
        </improve>
        <improve>Force select [i]APK files[/i] option in the restore tab if the apps aren't installed</improve>
        <fix>Fixed restoring backups with KeyStore</fix>
        <note subtext="true">Restoring KeyStore backups may not work if they are restored in a different device.</note>

        <!-- Activity Interceptor page -->
        <title type="medium">Activity Interceptor page</title>
        <new>Added option to create shortcuts and copy-and-paste contents</new>
        <note subtext="true">
            The copied text contains [tt]tab[/tt] separated entries. So, directly pasting them to messaging platforms
            may not work.
        </note>
        <new>Added [i]class[/i], [i]package[/i] and [i]identifier[/i] fields</new>
        <new>Added option to resolve and open activities using root</new>

        <!-- Running Apps page -->
        <title type="medium">Running Apps page</title>
        <new>Display memory (RAM) and swap information on top of the page</new>
        <new>
            View the details of a process by clicking on the item. For Android packages, the relevant App Info page
            can be accessed by tapping the [i]info[/i] button in the top-right corner of the sheet
        </new>
        <fix>Fixed detecting running apps with zygote preload</fix>

        <!-- Installer -->
        <title type="medium">Installer</title>
        <new>
            Added [i]App Info[/i] button in the top-right corner of the installation-completed dialog, which opens the
            App Details page
        </new>
        <improve>Added the ability to install multiple applications by maintaining a queue</improve>
        <improve>
            In Android 12 and later, applications previous installed with App Manager can be updated without any user
            interactions in the no-root mode
        </improve>
        <improve>Added the option to downgrade apps in the no-root mode</improve>
        <improve>Improved how splits are selected during installation</improve>
        <fix>Prevented the installer from hanging forever in the Knox-enabled Samsung devices</fix>
        <fix>Fixed support for applications uninstalled without clearing data</fix>
        <fix>Fixed handling applications with proof-of-rotation</fix>
        <fix>Fixed extracting OBB files</fix>

        <!-- Settings page -->
        <title type="medium">Settings</title>
        <new>
            Added [a href="app-manager://settings/saved_apk_format"]the option[/a] to specify
            a format for the APK files saved using batch operations or profiles
        </new>
        <new>
            Added [a href="app-manager://settings/selected_users"]the option[/a] to select
            the users App Manager should work with if the device has multiple users
        </new>
        <new>
            Added [a href="app-manager://settings/installer"]an option[/a] to block trackers
            immediately after installing an application if it is installed with App Manager's installer
        </new>
        <new>
            Added the option to select a [a
            href="app-manager://settings/rules_prefs/default_blocking_method"]default
            blocking method[/a]
        </new>
        <new>
            Added an option to reload apps in the [i]Troubleshooting[/i] category
        </new>
        <improve>
            Added [a href="app-manager://settings/installer"]the ability[/a] to install apps
            in the background
        </improve>
        <improve>Implement the new-style changelog</improve>
        <improve>Fallback to no-root mode if root or ADB is not detected.</improve>
        <improve>
            Full implementation of wireless debugging. See [a
            href="https://muntashirakon.github.io/AppManager/#sec:wireless-debugging"]docs[/a] for details
        </improve>
        <improve>Improved auto-detection of ADB</improve>
        <fix>Fixed changing application locale</fix>
        <fix>
            Fixed compatibility issues preventing pre-Marshmallow devices from displaying the [i]About the Device[/i]
            page
        </fix>
        <fix>Fixed importing keys from PKCS12 KeyStore file</fix>
        <fix>Fixed generating RSA keypair in Android Lollipop</fix>

        <!-- Others -->
        <title type="medium">Others</title>
        <new title="UI">Material 3 and dynamic colours</new>
        <new title="UI">
            Advanced searching and filtering, including the option to search by suffix, prefix or the regular
            expressions
        </new>
        <new title="1-Click Ops page">
            Added [i]Trim caches in all apps[/i] operation, which deletes the cache files of all applications, including
            Android system applications
        </new>
        <new title="Widget">A widget to help clear caches in all applications as in the 1-click ops page</new>
        <new title="Widget">
            A Digital Wellbeing-style widget with three resize options that displays the screen time along with the
            three mostly used applications
        </new>
        <new title="Documentation">New style single-page documentation</new>
        <new title="Language">Added Indonesian and Italian</new>
        <note subtext="true">Removed Bengali due to lack of translators.</note>
        <new title="Shared Preferences Editor">Added support for [tt]set[/tt] data</new>
        <new title="Profile page">
            Added [i]log viewer[/i] section where logs from the past profile triggers are displayed
        </new>
        <new title="Log Viewer">
            Changed extension of saved logs from [tt].log[/tt] to [tt].am.log[/tt] which can be opened in App Manager
            from the external apps or the system's [i]Sharing[/i] feature
        </new>
        <new title="Magisk">Added support for Magisk DenyList rules.</new>
        <new title="Magisk">Multi-process support for MagiskHide and Magisk DenyList</new>

        <improve title="App Usage page">Improved app usage details dialog to include more usage information</improve>
        <improve title="App Usage page">
            Data usage for mobile and Wi-Fi networks are shown with the Android phone and Wi-Fi icons respectively
            instead of the 'M' and 'W' prefixes
        </improve>
        <improve title="Documentation">Redirect to the docs site in case the WebView is unavailable</improve>
        <improve title="UI">
            Added Fast-scroller in the app info tab, the Running Apps page, the App Usage page and in the Manifest/Code
            Viewer page
        </improve>
        <improve title="UI">
            Key generator, changelog and about dialogs in the settings page are displayed in full-screen on small
            screens
        </improve>
        <improve title="Security">Use TLS 1.3 for connecting to ADB in Android 9 and later</improve>
        <improve title="Shared Preferences Editor">Display exit prompt if the file was edited</improve>
        <improve title="Scanner page">Display [tt].smali[/tt] content and a preview of its [tt].java[/tt] file</improve>
        <improve title="Scanner page">Renamed [i]Source Directory[/i] to [i]APK Checksums[/i]</improve>
        <improve title="Log Viewer">
            Clicking the settings menu opens the Log Viewer settings instead of the general settings page
        </improve>
        <improve title="Log Viewer">Replaced [b]Save Partial[/b] with multi-selection mode</improve>
        <improve title="UX">Improved navigating the app using a keyboard or a TV remote</improve>
        <improve title="Manifest Viewer">Reduced font-size to improve readability</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers and libraries</improve>

        <fix title="Manifest Viewer">Fixed displaying certain manifest files</fix>
        <fix title="Documentation">Fixed [i]File not found[/i] issue in some versions of Android</fix>
        <fix title="Language">Fixed punctuation issues in French</fix>
        <fix title="UI">Fix prominent RTL layout issues</fix>
        <fix>App Manager files are now cached in the cache directory instead of data directory</fix>
        <fix>fixed checking for root in some devices</fix>
        <fix>Fixed granting or revoking some app ops and permissions</fix>
        <fix>Fixed restoring application permissions while applying rules or restoring backups</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashes on attempting to disable net policies for the core applications</fix>

        <note>
            [br /][b]Full list of changes:[/b] [a
            href="https://github.com/MuntashirAkon/AppManager/compare/c504b30...v3.0.0"]v2.6.0...v3.0.0[/a]
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v2.6.0"
        code="385"
        date="25 Apr 2021">
        <new>
            [b]New Feature:[/b] Log Viewer (accessible from the main menu, “running” tag in the app info page and
            three-dots menu in each item of the running apps page).
        </new>
        <new>[b]New language:[/b] Arabic</new>
        <new>Added AES and RSA encryption (AES/GCM/NoPadding with 12 bytes IV) for backups</new>
        <new>Added clear cache option in ADB mode</new>
        <new>Added filter by profile in the main page</new>
        <new>Added options to disable log viewer</new>
        <new>
            Added the ability to import (JKS, BKS and PKCS #12 KeyStores and PK8 formatted private key and PEM
            certificate) and generate signing keys
        </new>
        <new>
            Added the option to import/export App Manager's KeyStore. It's a typical Bouncy Castle KeyStore in BKS
            extension
        </new>
        <new>
            Added SAF tag in the app info page for apps that uses storage access framework. Clicking on it lists the
            granted URIs.
        </new>
        <new>
            Added [b]Verify and redo backups[/b] and [b]back up apps with changes[/b] in 1-click ops page (in the backup
            section)
        </new>
        <improve>
            Removed UnAPKM from the app as newer APKMs are no longer encrypted. (Use UnAPKM extension from F-Droid to
            continue to decrypt the encrypted APKM files.)
        </improve>
        <improve>Added compatibility support for mobile data usage in old operating systems</improve>
        <improve>
            Added colour codes to the “backup” tag in the main page denoting the age of the backups: Red => Uninstalled,
            Dark cyan => Up to date backup, Orange => Outdated backup
        </improve>
        <improve>Added select all button in various multiple choice dialogs</improve>
        <improve>Display native libraries alongside shared libraries in the shared libs tab</improve>
        <improve>Display file names that could not be imported (when importing files from Blocker or Watt)</improve>
        <improve>Improved formatting of the backup info dialogs</improve>
        <improve>Moved usage access to enable/disable features in the settings page</improve>
        <improve>Organized settings by moving a rules and installer settings to a different fragment</improve>
        <improve>Replaced block trackers with block/unblock trackers</improve>
        <improve>Store backup hashes in the database to detect changes in data (will be enhanced in future)</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers and libraries</improve>
        <fix>Renamed global component blocking to instant component blocking</fix>
        <fix>Renamed [b]Backup APK[/b] to [b]Save APK[/b]</fix>
        <fix>Removed the backup option [b]Source[/b] and renamed [b]APK only[/b] to [b]APK files[/b]</fix>
        <fix>
            Replaced the backup option [b]Data[/b] with [b]Internal data[/b]. [b]External data[/b] no longer depends on
            this option
        </fix>
        <fix>Replaced the backup option [b]Exclude cache[/b] with [b]Cache[/b] (i.e., the flag has been inverted).</fix>
        <fix>Avoided crash in the app details page when device configuration (night mode, orientation, etc.) changes
        </fix>
        <fix>Backup URI grants only for the given users</fix>
        <fix>Fixed a crash occurs occasionally when detecting whether an app is running</fix>
        <fix>Fixed a crash when yesterday data isn't available in the app usage page</fix>
        <fix>
            Fixed a crash when back button is pressed immediately after pressing the add button in the profile page
        </fix>
        <fix>Fixed backup service from hanging if it encounters invalid file types</fix>
        <fix>Fixed fetching storage info for users other than the current user</fix>
        <fix>Fixed hidden API restriction bypass issue for Android 11 (which unfortunately increased the APK size)</fix>
        <fix>Fixed displaying wrong data usage in Android Lollipop devices</fix>
        <fix>Fixed restoring backups with symbolic links</fix>
        <fix>Foreground service notification is removed immediately after the operation is complete</fix>
        <note>
            [b]Notice:[/b] After restoring apps that use SAF and SSAID, the device has to be restarted immediately.
            Currently, the users are not notified if a restart is necessary after restoring a backup.
            If you are in confusion, make sure to restart your device after restoring a backup.
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="pre-release"
        version="v2.5.24"
        code="383"
        date="21 Mar 2021">
        <new>New language: Tradition Chinese</new>
        <new>Added filter by uninstalled apps, apps without backups in the main page</new>
        <new>Allow specifying custom installer package which may or may not be installed</new>
        <new>Copy package name on clicking on the package name in the app info tab</new>
        <new>Display file size, requirement, etc. for split APKs in the APK selection dialog</new>
        <new>Display version and tracker info in the installation confirmation dialog</new>
        <improve>
            Added wildcard support for app ops and permissions for profiles. [tt]*[/tt] can be used instead of
            specifying app ops or permissions to revoke all configured/dangerous permissions/app ops
        </improve>
        <improve>App icons are cached to improve load time</improve>
        <improve>Complete rewrite of running apps internals in Java</improve>
        <improve>Display uninstalled system apps and display installation prompt on clicking them</improve>
        <improve>Improved ADB detection and persistence of such detection</improve>
        <improve>Removed toybox along with its dependencies</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers and libraries</improve>
        <improve>Utilise multiple CPUs for back up/restore</improve>
        <improve>
            Verify copied checksum with the checksum of the signing certificate of the app on clicking on the app icon
            in the app info page
        </improve>
        <fix>Added additional verifications to ensure that screen lock is not bypassed</fix>
        <fix>Fixed back up/restore failure on some Android devices</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashes in the app details page when system configuration changes</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crash on creating shortcuts on devices that do not support pin shortcut</fix>
        <fix>Fixed generating wrong checksum for certificates in the signatures tab</fix>
        <fix>Fixed uninstalling app for multiple users</fix>
        <fix>Fixed various crashes on opening APK files from external apps</fix>
        <fix>Hide backup option if one of the selected apps is not installed</fix>
        <fix>Verify KeyStore backups during restoring a backup</fix>
    </release>
    <release
        type="pre-release"
        version="v2.5.23"
        code="381"
        date="4 Feb 2021">
        <new>Added screen lock</new>
        <new>Added [b]Add to profile[/b] in the batch ops and app info tab</new>
        <new>Added enable/disable features in settings (replacing interceptor setting)</new>
        <new>Added leanback launcher support with banner (Android TV)</new>
        <new>Backup/restore SSAID (requires immediate restart)</new>
        <new>Backup APK in external SD card</new>
        <new>
            AppInfo: Added options to configure battery optimization, net policy, SSAID. For each of them, tag clouds
            will be displayed if the values are not default.
        </new>
        <new>Interceptor: add/remove extras</new>
        <new>Made settings page accessible from Android Settings</new>
        <new>
            Main: Added filter by installed app, sort by number of trackers and last actions (the latter is not stable
            yet)
        </new>
        <new>New language: Japanese</new>
        <new>Search using app initials in the main page (e.g. TS will list TrebleShot in the search results)</new>
        <new>Use of database as a middle man to improve load time</new>
        <improve>AppInfo: Added options to select tracker components to block/unblock</improve>
        <improve>Improved backup volume selection</improve>
        <improve>
            Main: Batch selection on long click after the selection mode is turned on (i.e. selection mode is turned on
            if you click on any app icon or long click on any app)
        </improve>
        <improve>Main: Replaced sort and filter with list options</improve>
        <improve>Main: Set [b]backup[/b] to red if the app is not installed</improve>
        <improve>Removed F-Droid, Aurora Droid in favour of F-Droid links (to support user preferred clients)</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers, libraries, profile presets</improve>
        <fix>Fixed app icon (it now matches app theme)</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crash while blocking app components of a recently updated app</fix>
        <fix>Fixed various crashes in the app info tab</fix>
        <fix>Properly sanitize profile names and exported APK(S) file names</fix>
        <fix>Remove rules for all users (rather than the current user) in settings</fix>
        <fix>Replaced AppManager/tmp with AppManager/.tmp</fix>
        <fix>Replaced image buttons with material buttons (fixes crash when using Substratum themes)</fix>
        <note>
            Don't set folders inside [tt]/mnt/media_rw/[/tt] as the backup volume. It doesn't work for backup/restore.
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="pre-release"
        version="v2.5.22"
        code="379"
        date="16 Jan 20201">
        <new>1-Click Ops: add backup/restore options</new>
        <new>Added the ability to freeze backup (by creating [tt].freeze[/tt] in the corresponding backup)</new>
        <new>Added option to enable/disable MagiskHide in the App Info tab (enable option in the overflow menu)</new>
        <new>Added option to enable/disable interceptor (in settings)</new>
        <new>Added option to launch services</new>
        <new>Added option to select backup volume</new>
        <new>Backup/restore app installer, netpolicy, deviceidle, magiskhide and notification access</new>
        <new>Backup/restore URI grants (need immediate reboot after the restore)</new>
        <new>Grant/revoke permissions in profile</new>
        <new>New attribute in backup/restore: size</new>
        <new>New attribute in profile: users</new>
        <new>New tag in App Info: backups</new>
        <improve>Added encryption info in about device</improve>
        <improve>Block and disable components using IFW and PackageManager respectively for maximum protection</improve>
        <improve>Improved instructions in the 1-Click Ops page</improve>
        <improve>Integrated docs within AM as a dynamic feature</improve>
        <improve>Open DRM-free APKM files without conversion</improve>
        <improve>Sort apps by labels, display user/system tag in the profile page</improve>
        <improve>Replace backup all users with custom users</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers and libraries</improve>
        <improve>
            Remove [tt]FLAG_ACTIVITY_FORWARD_RESULT[/tt] from list of flags (if present) in the interceptor
        </improve>
        <fix>Add [tt].nomedia[/tt] file in the backup folder</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crash on clicking [i]about device[/i] item in Settings</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crash in the profile page</fix>
        <fix>Fixed compatibility issue of IFW in Android M or prior versions</fix>
        <fix>Get correct user ID before performing uninstall</fix>
        <fix>Migrate to PackageManager API instead of using unreliable pm command</fix>
        <fix>Update theme name on changing app theme</fix>
        <fix>Use package name from metadata instead of directory name for backups</fix>
        <note>
            Backup/restore feature is now beta. From now on, backward compatibility for backup/restorer will be
            provided.
        </note>
    </release>
    <release
        type="pre-release"
        version="v2.5.21"
        code="377"
        date="1 Jan 2021">
        <new>New language: Farsi</new>
        <new>Added about device in the settings page</new>
        <new>Added an installation button in the scanner page for the external APK files</new>
        <new>Added the option to set custom app ops and modes in the three-dots menu</new>
        <improve>Added shortcut support for Android N MR1 or less</improve>
        <improve>Display app ops associated with the declared permissions in the app ops tab</improve>
        <improve>Display feature availability and version number in the uses features tab</improve>
        <improve>Display icon for uninstalled but backed up apps in the main page</improve>
        <improve>Display tracker count in a new line instead of under brackets in the 1-click ops page</improve>
        <improve>Improved app install time for ADB users</improve>
        <improve>
            Renamed “deny app ops” to “set mode for app ops”, added the option to specify modes in 1-click ops page
        </improve>
        <improve>Reordered backup options along with description for each items</improve>
        <improve>Updated ADBLib</improve>
        <improve>Updated trackers and libraries</improve>
        <fix>Fixed crashes of the app ops tab in Android 11</fix>
        <fix>Fixed crashes of the app ops tab in MIUI</fix>
        <fix>Fixed prompting users for ADB permission repeatedly when auto is the mode of operation</fix>
        <fix>Hide launch and shortcut buttons from the activities tab for external APK</fix>
        <fix>Use both package mode and UID mode for app ops from Android 6</fix>
        <fix>Use data folder to store server/IPC related files</fix>
    </release>
</changelog>